Cambridge, MA 02141 201.669.1680 j.skrable@gmail.com

Talented and innovative data engineer and integration developer with 5 years of professional experience building and using ETL processes and RESTful APIs. In my current role, I quickly mastered the industry leading SnapLogic integration platform for use by many disparate clients for Boston University. I continually work to design, optimize and improve processes. I learn rapidly, think broadly, and develop with an attention to detail.

# **Professional Experience**

Boston University Boston, MA

Programmer Analyst III

Feb 2020 - Present

• Created a generic integration logging pipeline and designed a common logging data model to collect, analyze, and distribute integration run logs among stakeholders, saving time and promoting interaction between departments.

Programmer Analyst II

July 2018 – Feb 2020

- REST API developed for university research cloud migration, using JavaScript, JSON, Active Directory, and PostgreSQL
- Led team of developers to implement a self-service portal using for university integration consumers. Hosted as static site on AWS, automated deployment using a continuous integration pipeline.
- Developed an integration to move resume data from complex type XML to JSON to SQL server DB using JavaScript and Python within SnapLogic. Modularized into REST APIs to allow for consumption across the university as a microservice.

Programmer Analyst I April 2017 – July 2018

- Designed and implemented integration to move complex college applicant data from mainframe to Salesforce, using JSON and JavaScript within SnapLogic; maintaining a canonical data model throughout.
- Design and implementation of university wide integration platform using iPaaS industry leader SnapLogic
- Created integration reporting database for campus-wide integrations across multiple platforms
- Design and development of generalized file transport platform for use by departments all over the university

### **WGBH Educational Foundation**

Boston, MA

Senior Support and Data Analyst

Nov 2016 - March 2017

- Developed method to capture subscriptions from web forms, leverage donor matching process, and transmit to Salesforce using RESTful Web Services to distribute marketing data among employees and increase overall donor engagement
- Implement automated sync process between Salesforce and data warehouse using mix of web services and ETL tools
- Demonstrate and exhibit various software products and proprietary data operations for prospective clients
- Orchestrated full SQL Server database implementation, including architecture, tuning, software and roles install, public and private facing web site creation using IIS, and troubleshooting.

Support and Data Analyst

Jan 2015 - Nov 2016

- Provide prompt and thorough technical support for WGBH and external stations' donor database platform, focused on
  efficient and accurate communication between Salesforce front-end and SQL Server data warehouse
- Perform full database conversions from various client sources (Oracle, MySQL) into Salesforce
- · Enhance and refine heuristic matching operations for incoming and existing accounts, contacts, and leads
- Orchestrated full remote server database implementation for high-volume client, including architecture and tuning
- Created automation to sniff for encrypted files dropped onto FTP site and decrypt the files using GNU PGP

### **Technologies**

Python, Javascript, Java, C, PySpark, TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Flask, React, JQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, MVC, HTML, CSS, REST, SOAP, Linux, Bash, Windows, \*SQL, S3, Aurora, Lambda, API Gateway, SnapLogic, Salesforce

# **Education**

## **Boston University**

Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.97

Sep 2017 - Jan 2020

*Projects*: Music Recommendation Using Deep Learning Neural Network, Traveling Salesman Solution Using Simulated Annealing, RSA and El Gamal Cryptography, Genetic Algorithm to Mimic Fish Schooling Behavior, Sarcasm Detection in Headlines Using PySpark

## **Boston University**

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Information Systems and Entrepreneurship

Sep 2010 – May 2014